游戏结束
Game over.
我他妈的一定要杀了你！
I'll fuckin' kill you!
你这他妈的混蛋！
You fuckin' bitch!
你这婊子！
You bitch!
我他妈的一定要杀了你！
I'll fuckin' kill you!
丹尼尔！
Daniel!
《电锯惊魂3》
注意侧边！ 左边安全？
Secure the flank! Left side clear?
安全！
We're clear!
左边安全！ 行动！
Left side's clear. Let's move!
噢 上帝
Oh, my God.
谁去把凯莉找来
Someone call Kerry.
电话是11：45打来的 一个女的听到了爆炸声
The call came in at 11:45. The woman heard an explosion.
最先到现场的是消防队
The fire department was the first on the scene.
凯莉
Kerry.
- 是他吗？ - 在你进去之前…
- Is it him? - Before you go in there…
埃里克 是不是他？
Eric. Is it him?
我们现在还确定不了
We don't know yet.
不是马修斯探员
It's not Detective Matthews.
这儿发生了什么？
What happened?
受害者被铁链穿透 并绑在这里
The victim was held in place by these chains.
你好 特洛伊
Hello, Troy.
我想和你做个游戏
I wanna play a game.
游戏将会在一个不大的地方里进行
This game will take place in a room not much bigger.
这地方比起你大半 生都待的地方…
than the room you've spent most of your life in.
监狱的牢房 要小一点
A prison cell.
不管老天赋予你
Despite all of the advantages and privileges.
多少优势和特权
that you were given at birth,
你总是屡教不悔 一次次的被关进监狱
you have returned to prison again and again.
也许拿铁链这么穿着你 比让你自由还舒服吧
More comfortable in chains than you are in freedom.
今晚 我们来看看 一旦你挣脱铁链
Tonight we will see how far you are willing to go.
你能走多远
to break those chains once and for all.
是生是死
Live or die, Troy.
你自己定
Make your choice.
这是炸弹
This was the bomb.
他所要做的就是挣脱掉铁链…
All he had to do was release himself from each of the chains…
并在炸弹爆炸之前走出门
walk out the door before it went off.
他所要做的？
All he had to do?
哦 上帝
Oh, God.
操！操！
Fuck! Fuck!
我真有种感觉 感觉马修斯也出事了
I really had this feeling it was going to be him.
凯莉 埃里克的案子是一 件失踪案而不是谋杀案
Kerry, Eric is a missing persons case, not a homicide case.
我总能做恶梦看见他
I've been having nightmares where I see him.
我总原谅不了自己
I'm never going to be able to forgive myself for what happened.
听着 这不是你的错
Listen. It's not your fault.
可这总是谁的错吧
It's always somebody's fault.
但那人不是你
That somebody isn't you.
那个罪人还在逍遥法外
That someone is still out there.
你要把你所有的怒气都用在找到他们 并收拾他们
Put all your anger into finding them and putting them away.
好吗？
All right?
我不明白的是
What I don't understand is.
“竖锯”是怎么做到的？
how the hell could Jigsaw do all of this?
我们上次看着他的时候 他不是已经快不行了吗？
He was damn near on his deathbed the last time we saw him.
我不太肯定是他干的
I'm not so sure he did.
至少 这看起来不像是他的手法
So far this doesn't follow any of his patterns.
意思是？
Meaning?
哇哦…你们是怎么进来的？
Well… how'd you get in here?
- 我们弄断了门 - 为什么？
- We cut the door down. - Why?
因为有人听到了爆炸声并打了电话给我们
Because somebody heard an explosion and called us.
我是说 你们为什么要把门弄断？
I mean, why did you have to cut the door down?
门给焊死了
It was welded shut.
该死的卡车也撞不进来
Bloody truck couldn't get in here.
没错
Exactly.
我不明白
I don't follow.
游戏的目的是在炸弹爆炸前离开
If the aim of Jigsaw's game was to get out before the bomb went off,
那为什么还要把门焊死？
then why was the door welded shut?
那人想出去都出不去
The guy couldn't get out if he wanted to.
你们不会相信的 那盘录像带安然无恙
You won't believe this. We got the tape out clean.
你好 特洛伊 我想玩个游戏
Hello, Troy. I wanna play a game.
是死是活 特洛伊 你自己定
Live or die, Troy. Make your choice.
你好 凯莉
Hello, Kerry.
我想玩个游戏
I want to play a game.
至今 你的大部分生命都在和死人打交道
Up until now you have spent your life among the dead.
拼凑着他们生前的最后一刻
piecing together their final moments.
你擅长这个 因为你喜欢死人
You are good at this because you, like them,
或者说 你也死了
are also dead.
内心已死
Dead on the inside.
和活人相比
You identify more with a cold corpse.
你更像具冰冷的尸体
than you do with a living human.
我相信 你想加入你真正的家庭
I believe you want to join your true family,
真正的 你唯一的家庭 死亡
indeed, your only family, in death.
你所穿的装置
The device you are wearing.
紧紧钩住了你的胸腔
is hooked into your ribcage.
并且 在这段录像播完后
And by the time this tape is finished,
你将有一分钟的时间去找出路
you will have one minute to find a way out.
那一分钟结束后 你应该…
At the end of that minute, you should know.
比任何人都清楚 会发生什么
better than anyone what happens then.
那有一把小小的钥匙 可以打开这器具 凯莉
There is a simple key that will unlock the harness, Kerry.
它就在你面前
It is right in front of you.
你所要做的就是把手伸进去 并把它拿出来
All you have to do is reach in and take it.
但是要快一点
But do it quickly.
里面的酸剂会在几秒内把钥匙溶解
The acid will dissolve the key in a matter of seconds.
你自己选择吧
Make your choice.
你
You.
我九点就得到医院
I gotta be at the hospital by 9.
今天是星期二 我以为你十一点上班
It's Tuesday. I thought you started at 11.
是啊 不错 但他们最后通知我调班
Yeah, well, they change things on me last minute.
哇哦 那你就别理它了
Well, you better head off, then.
你不打算洗个澡了？
You're not gonna take a shower?
不了 我到医院里面去洗
Nah. I'm just gonna take a shower at the hospital.
我们能不能… 好好谈个五分钟？
Can we just… talk for five minutes?
我们就这么花个 五秒钟看着对方怎么样？
How about we just make eye contact for five seconds?
怎么了？
What's wrong?
没事 只是…所有事
Nothing. Just… everything.
莲恩
Lynn.
你到底想要我怎么样 克里斯？
What is it you want from me, Chris?
离婚
A divorce.
急诊
MPA.
车祸
Car skidded into oncoming traffic.
血压？
Pressure?
８０完毕 心率仪准备完毕
80 over, palp. Pulse is thready.
好了吗？1 2 3
Ready? 1, 2, 3.
- 莲恩医生在哪？ - 呼叫莲恩医生
- Where's Lynn? - Page Dr. Denlon.
广播通知
Set up an art-line.
莲恩·戴伦医生
Dr. Lynn Denlon,
请速至外伤科报道
please report to trauma immediately.
莲恩·戴伦医生 请速至外伤科报道
Dr. Lynn Denlon, please report to trauma immediately.
莲恩
Lynn!
检查这个 镇痛剂
Check this out. Hermaphony.
血压下降到70 他要休克了
Pressure down to 70. He's going into shock.
准备手术室 我们要进行开胸
Get an OR ready. We gotta crack his chest.
有没有反刍血块？ ５００cc左右？
Do we get a bolus? 500 wide open?
不
No.
什么？
What?
- 右侧没有气胸 - 然后呢？
- No air entry on the right side. - And?
插入气管就行
Let's get a chest tube in him.
我们得马上把他送到手术室去
We gotta get him to OR now.
他的指数在下降 体温过低
His stats are dropping. He's gonna code.
我正在处理
I'm doin' it.
我要给他吸氧
I'm getting a rush of air.
指数回升 血压回升至80
Stats are improving. Pressure back to 80.
血压正常
Pressure normal.
听着 如果你有什么不顺心的事 到楼上找心理医生说去
If you got something on your mind, go upstairs to psych.
别把情绪带到这儿来
Just don't bring it in here.
我们是在争分夺秒 莲恩
We don't have any seconds to spare, Lynn.
是不是你必须得被人
The woman standing in front of me had to be dragged.
从更衣室给拽出来 才愿意把胸管插给外伤病人？
from the locker room to put a chest tube in a trauma patient?
莲恩·戴伦 应该是第一个在场的人
Lynn Denlon should have been the first one there.
莲恩
Lynn.
莲恩！
Lynn!
真见鬼！
What the hell?
我被锁在里面了！
I'm locked in!
外面有人吗？
Is anybody there?
喂！
Hello?
外面有人吗？
Anybody here?
救命！救我！
Help! Help me!
救命！
Help!
你是谁？ 你是谁？
Who are you? Who are you?
这是什么？
What is this?
你要干嘛？
What are you doing?
你能老实点吗？
Are you gonna behave?
走吧
Let's go.
这是什么地方？ 这是什么地方？
What is this place? What is this place?
这是…什么地方？
What is… this place?
你是谁？ 你是谁？
Who are you? Who are you?
你好 莲恩·戴伦医生
Hello, Dr. Denlon.
你可能不记得我了 但我可是清清楚楚地记得你
You may not remember me, but I most certainly remember you.
我曾经是你们医院的一位病人
I was a guest at your hospital once.
我在哪里？
Where am I?
你记得我吗？
Do you remember me?
（恶性脑肿瘤）
（莲恩医生）
（约翰·克莱默）
我在电视里见过你
I've seen you on television.
劳伦斯·戈登是你的医生
Lawrence Gordon was your doctor.
我曾是他的病人 他曾是我的医生
I was his patient, and he was mine.
从病历上来看
As you can see from that report,
我的诊断结果不是很好
my prognosis isn't good.
你同意吗？
Would you agree?
（严重压迫脑干）
（多形性恶性胶质瘤）
（已转移 绝症）
你患得是不治之症
There's no preventative treatment for what you have.
我记得你以前也这么说过
I remember you saying that to me once before.
几乎是一个语气
in almost the exact same tone.
并把我丢给了另一个医生 让他 用冷冰冰的医学术语
Leave it to a doctor to find such a cold, clinical way.
告诉我 自己正在步向死亡
of saying I'm a dead man walking.
看着我 你觉得我还能活多久？
Looking at me, how long would you say I have left?
我得要检查一下
I'd have to examine you.
不过就算检查了 额叶肿瘤也是无法预测的
Even then, a frontal lobe tumor is unpredictable.
生长的速度要依靠癌细胞的 分裂程度和其吞噬结果来决定…
The growth depends on the rate of mitosis versus apoptosis…
我很抱歉 但这儿的较差的医疗设备
I'm sorry, but there's all this crude medical equipment around me.
让你以为自己还身处医院
causing you to believe that you're still inside a hospital.
不
No.
那你为什么还
Then why are you speaking to me.
用那医学术语给我放屁？
in that graduate school medical jargon?
看着我！
Look at me!
看着我
Now, you look at me.
我问你一个简单的问题
I asked you a simple question.
凭你的经验
Based on your experience,
你认为我还能活多久？
how long do you think I have left?
这不是那么简单就能回答的
It's not a simple answer.
根据你的档案 我认为…活不长
Based on your file, I'd say… not long.
死亡是个令人惊喜聚会
Death is a surprise party.
当然 除非 你内心已死
Unless, of course, you're already dead on the inside.
除非你是那种
Unless you're the type of person.
吞食着止痛片来麻木自己的人 啊？
who swallows antidepressants to hide the pain, huh?
背叛丈夫
Turns their back on their husband.
不管孩子
Neglects their child.
有着绝佳的条件
Who has every possible advantage in life.
却不思进取
but chooses not to advance.
你想要我怎么样？
What do you want from me?
我想怎么样？
What do I want?
我想玩个游戏
I want to play a game.
游戏规则很简单
The rules of the game are simple.
违规的结果就是终极的
The consequences for breaking them are great.
死亡
Death.
你将被考验 你的意志将被考验
You're being tested. Your will is being tested.
你将要使一个人活着
Your will to keep someone alive.
你能做到吗？
Can you do that?
你能遵守规则 接受生命给予的馈赠吗？
Can you follow the rules and grant someone the gift of life?
这是什么？ 不！把它…
What is this? No! Get it…
不！不！这是什么！ 你要对我做什么？
No! No! What is this! What are you doing to me?
你穿的装置与我的心率监控器相连
The device that you're wearing is linked to my heart rate monitor.
一旦我心跳消失 或者你走出了限定范围
The second that heart rate monitor flatlines or you move out of range,
项圈就会爆炸
an explosion will go off in that collar.
你和我的生命都将同时结束
Your life and my life will end simultaneously.
求你了 求你别这样
Please. Please don't do this to me.
我有一个家庭 我有一个家庭
I have a family. I have a family.
让我换个简单的说法告诉你吧
Let me give you the simple version.
你要不惜一切代价的让他活着
You will keep him alive, whatever it takes.
不许找借口 不许装糊涂
No excuses. No equivocations.
不许哭喊
No crying.
你什么意思 让他活到什么时候？
What do you mean, keep him alive?
那边的监视器里面 我们有另外一个考验对象
Out there, on those screens, we have another test subject.
一个男人
A man.
他将面对一系列的考验
He will face a series of tests.
你要让约翰活下去直到那人完全通过
You have to keep John alive until he makes it through.
如果他完成了所有的考验 而且约翰还有气的话
If he completes all of his tests and John is still breathing,
那我就会解下你的项圈…
then I will remove your collar…
你就可以走了
and you're free to go.
你是我谜题中至关 重要的一块 戴伦医生
You're a vital piece of my puzzle, Dr. Denlon.
可能是我最后考验中的最重要部分
A critical part of what could be my final test.
阿曼达 是时候开始我们的游戏了
Amanda, it's time to start our game.
救命！
Help!
喂！
Hello!
外面有人吗？
Is there anybody out there?
你好 杰夫
Hello, Jeff.
在过去的几年里
Over the past few years,
你让自己成了生活中 空壳般的行尸走肉…
you have become a shell of your former self…
内心充斥着憎恨和复仇
consumed with hatred and vengeance.
憎恨着那个喝醉酒并撞死你儿子的司机
Vengeance against the drunk driver who killed your only son.
出于你的惊讶和沮丧 你憎恨着 这个杀手
Vengeance against the killer, who to your surprise and dismay,
在草率审判后被判无罪释放
was set free after a hasty trial.
然而 今天 轮到了你来接受审判
Today, however, it is you who will be put on trial.
要逃离这地方 你将面对一系列的考验
To escape from where you are, you will have to face a series of tests.
你将在通过每个关卡 时受到煎熬般的考验
You will have to suffer to move forward through each of them.
但是每次考验 你都会有一次机会…
But with each one, you will also have a chance…
一次去原谅的机会
a chance to forgive.
当你完成所有考验时
When you complete the tests,
我向你保证 你将最终和一个人面对面
I promise you you will finally come face to face.
这个人应对你失去的孩子的死 负全部责任
with the man responsible for the loss of your child.
那将是你最终的考验
That will be your ultimate test.
你能原谅他吗？
Can you forgive him?
不过你最好抓紧点
You better hurry, though.
两个小时后 门就会锁住
In two hours, the doors will lock,
这地方就将会成为你的坟墓
and this place will become your tomb.
这是你一直以来所期待的 杰夫
This is what you've been waiting for, Jeff.
让游戏开始吧！
Let the game begin.
救命！
Help!
你他妈的杀了我儿子
You fucking killed my son.
你他妈还不求饶？
Don't you fuckin' beg.
知道我是谁吗？
Do you know who I am?
让我来教教你 你着该死的混蛋！
I'll fuckin' teach you, you motherfucker.
这就是你他妈想要的
This is what you fuckin' deserve.
在哪？
Where is it?
什么？
What?
它在哪？
Where is it?
多少次了
How many times?
我告诉你多少次了
How many times do I have to tell you.
什么时候你才能记住？
before you get it in your head?
我只是想找个东西陪我睡觉
I just wanted to sleep with something.
不 不 你只是…没事
No. No. You just… nothin'.
你只是不要…碰迪伦房间里的东西
You don't… touch things in Dylan's room.
好吗？
Okay?
对不起 爸爸
I'm sorry, Daddy.
你知道我是爱你的 对吗？
You know I love you, don't you?
要是妈妈看到我们这样会怎么想？
What do you think Mommy would say if she saw us like this?
我去准备上学了
I'm gonna go get ready for school.
爸爸！
Daddy!
喂？
Hello?
嘿！
Hey!
（打开门 杰夫）
好了 约翰 我要你看着我的鼻子
All right, John. I need you to look at my nose.
这边
Right here.
请看着我的鼻子
Look at my nose, please?
跟着我的手电光
Follow my flashlight.
疼的话就告诉我 好吗？
Tell me if you feel any pain, all right?
疼吗？
That hurt?
开始了
It's begun.
他从箱子里出来了
He's out of the box.
怎么样？
So?
没有任何医学设备的 情况下我的简短诊断
My 20-second analysis without any medical equipment.
他是脑内梗阻
is that his brain's herniating.
他需要去医院动手术
He needs to go to the hospital and have an operation.
来给他的脑颅减压
to decompress his brain.
过来
Come here.
- 不 真的 过来 - 什么？
- No, really. Come here. - What?
- 过来 - 不
- Come here. - No.
- 让我问问你 - 哦 上帝啊
- Let me ask you something. - Oh, God!
是我把约翰带来找你的…
Did I bring John to you…
还是我带你这混蛋找他？
or did I bring your self-centered ass to him?
你最好给我放明白点
You better start fuckin' paying attention.
没有人会去医院
No one's going to any hospital.
我不会创造奇迹
I can't perform miracles.
你…你在给他吃止疼片
You're… You're giving him painkillers.
像这样的肿瘤 他需要激素 比如强的松
For a tumor like this, he needs steroids, Prednisone.
哦 好吧 行
Oh, good. Yeah.
或许我们可以试试肾上腺皮质脂醇 什么的
Maybe we could try some corticoid steroids,
你知道 比如地赛米松
you know, like Dexamethasone.
你为什么他妈的要 跟我讲我不明白的东西
Why don't you fuckin' tell me something that I don't know,
你这混蛋
you stupid cunt?
只有一个地方可以找到这些药物 那就是医院
The only place that he can get those drugs is in a hospital.
不然他会死的
Or else he's gonna die.
你可不是一个好听众
You are not a good listener.
我想你错过一些 东西 他要是死了…
I think you missed the part that if he dies…
你也得死
you die.
你在要求我做不可能的事情
You're asking me to do the impossible.
不是我在要求 是他
I'm not asking you. He is.
他选择了你
He chose you.
- 不是我 - 阿曼达！
- Not me. - Amanda!
我的医生不能做被要求做事
Our doctor can't do what's being asked of her.
如果你威胁她的话
if you're threatening her.
我们游戏的规则很清楚
The rules of our game have been made very clear.
你必须得遵守规则
You need to abide by those rules.
对不起
Sorry.
阿曼达！ 阿曼达！我需要你帮忙
Amanda! Amanda, I need your help!
阿曼达！他需要氧气
Amanda, he needs oxygen!
氧气 阿曼达！
Oxygen, Amanda!
把面罩盖在他脸上
Put the mask on his face.
Okay，我要你把他按住
Okay, now hold him down.
让他的头靠一边 好了吗？
Tip his head to the side. You got it?
你在干什么？
What are you doing?
氯羟安定！ 你有没有氯羟安定？
Ativan! Do you have Ativan?
没有！
No!
后退！后退！
Back off! Back off!
坚持住！约翰
Stay with me, John.
坚持住！约翰 你能挺过来
You're almost through this. Stay with me.
挺住！ 没事了
Stay with me. We're almost done with this.
刚才的够了吗？
Was that enough for you?
你现在准备去医院了吗？
Are you ready to go to the hospital now?
他需要动手术
He needs to have an operation.
- 好吧 - 好吧
- Okay. - Okay.
但是得在这儿做
But we do it here.
- 我们在这里做 - 什么？
- We do it here. - What?
你需要什么？
What do you need?
这样的手术 我需要麻醉剂
I need anesthetic for a procedure like this.
麻醉剂 还要什么？
Anesthetic. What else?
就算有了麻醉剂…
Even with an anesthetic…
麻醉剂！还要什么？
Anesthetic! What else?
电钻
A power drill.
（直面你的恐惧）
噢 我得天 噢 我得天
Oh, my God. Oh, my God.
求你 求你了 让我走
Please, please. Let me go.
求你了 为什么…为什么 你这样对我？
Please. Why… Why are you doing this to me?
不要…不要杀我 好吗？求你了！
Don't… Don't kill me. Okay? Please!
等等 钥匙 钥匙
Wait. The key. Key.
钥匙 好的 快了
Key. Okay. Come on.
妈的！
Fuck!
求你了 我快被冻死了 我的胳膊已经没有知觉了
Please. I'm so cold. I can't feel my arms.
欢迎来到你的第一个考验 杰夫
Welcome to your first test, Jeff.
过去三年里 你一直在诅咒那些名字…
For the past three years, you've cursed the name.
那些你觉得应该为…
of all those you thought were responsible.
你儿子的死负责的人
for the death of your son.
你觉得那些人应该遭受报应
You fantasize those accountable will pay.
那好 你会看到你面前 有个女人被铁链绑住了
Well, you will find a woman in front of you chained in place.
那是为了不让她跑掉…
This will prevent her from running…
这样她就不能像以前你儿子 被撞时她逃离了现场那样了
much like she did on the day your son was hit.
她的名字叫戴尼卡·斯考特
Her name is Danica Scott.
她是唯一的…
She was the only witness present.
在你儿子出事现场的目击者
at the scene of your son's untimely demise.
要不是她的自私自利和胆小怕事
If not for her own self-absorption and cowardice,
她理应出庭作证 将凶手绳之以法
she could have brought your son's killer to justice.
现在这正是你仅有的 将她正法的机会
Now it is you who has a chance to bring her to justice.
当然你也可以在她 被冻死前赐予她生命
You alone can grant her the gift of life before she freezes to death.
在后墙的水管背后
Behind the pipes on the back wall.
你可以找到一把钥匙 它可以释放她 并
you will find the key that will free her and bring you.
可以让你进一步接近
one step closer to the man.
那个应对你不幸的孩子负责的人
responsible for the loss of your child.
你是准备留着钥匙 只救你自己呢？
Will you claim the key to save only yourself?
救我！
Help me!
还是能良心发现 再多救几个人？
Or can you find it within you to save another?
你自己做决定吧
Make your choice.
我什么都没干
I didn't do anything.
我对你什么都没做过！
I didn't do anything to you!
没错 就是因为你什么也没做
That's exactly it. You didn't do anything.
我他妈的就要…死了
I'm fucking… dying.
他死了！
He died!
死在我的怀里
In my arms.
我八岁大的儿子死在了我得怀里
My eight-year-old son died in my arms.
我犯了个、个、个错
I made a m-m-mistake.
我很抱歉
I'm so sorry.
我也是人啊
I'm human.
我也是人啊 就像你的儿子 不是吗？
I'm human, just like your son was. Okay?
看着我
Look at me.
我说 看着我 看…
I said, look at me. Look…
噢 上帝
Oh, my God.
太冷了
It's so cold.
噢 上帝！
Oh, God!
（一颗子弹可以结束一切）
阿曼达 你如果真的关心约翰
Amanda, if you really care about John,
就别让我这样做
you won't let me do this to him.
你是个聪明的女人
You're a smart woman,
而且你也知道怎样才是对他好
and you know what's right for him.
对不起
I'm sorry.
我知道那样很难集中注意力
I know it's hard to concentrate.
因为你身边有那么多可以杀我的东西
when you're surrounded by so many things you could kill me with,
就像这把斧子 我知道你一直在看它
like this ax I saw you lookin' at.
拿着
Take it.
请便 它是你的
Please, it's yours.
来吧
Come on.
虽然我砍脖子
I'd go for the neck,
但我不是脑外科医生
but I'm not the brain surgeon.
只是砍的时候小声点 别让约翰听见我死了
Just do it quietly so John doesn't hear me die.
不然 他很可能会生气
Otherwise he's likely to get upset,
扯下他的心率监测器
rip off his heart rate monitor.
嘭
Boom.
到时候你只要找到 并解除传感器
Then you just have to find the sensor and disarm it.
那样你就可以离门 走出三十英尺以上了
so you can walk more than 30 feet out that door.
而且也没有了爆炸的威胁
without the collar detonating.
或者你也可以试着自己卸掉项圈
Or you could try and take the collar off yourself.
但那会有点棘手
But that could be tricky.
有一点轻微的触动在错误的 位置时都会引发装置的爆炸
The slightest knock in the wrong place could trigger it.
我很清楚
I should know.
因为是我造的
I built it.
所以 你要的东西都全了吗？
So, do you have everything you need?
那些只能让我把他脑袋打开
I have the instruments to cut someone open.
但那些却不足以保住他的命
I don't have the tools to save a life.
你会惊奇的发现什么 才是保住性命的工具
You'd be surprised what tools can save a life.
你好 阿曼达
Hello, Amanda.
你不认识我 但…我认识你
You don't know me, but… I know you.
我想玩个游戏
I want to play a game.
那只有一把钥匙能打开装置
There is only one key to open the device.
它就在你死去狱友的胃内
It's in the stomach of your dead cellmate.
看看四周吧 阿曼达
Look around, Amanda.
你就知道我没有骗你
Know that I'm not playing.
是生是死
Live or die.
你自己选择
Make your choice.
恭喜
Congratulations.
你还活着
You are still alive.
大部分人都不知感激自己还活着
Most people are so ungrateful to be alive,
但不是你 至少不再是了
but not you, not anymore.
阿曼达 别怕
Amanda, do not be afraid.
你的人生的价值才刚刚开始
Your life has just begun.
他通过冷藏室了
He made it through the freezer room.
他曾努力去救她
He tried to save her.
我需要你为我做一些事
There are some things I need you to do for me.
在我桌子… 中间的抽屉里
In my desk… in the center drawer,
有个信封…
an envelope…
上面有你的名字
with your name on it.
她要给你动手术
She's gonna do a procedure on you.
行
Yeah.
给你的脑颅减压
To relieve the pressure on your brain.
好
Yeah.
并且去除头痛
And help with the headaches.
我做不来
I can't do this.
阿曼达…你可以
Amanda… you can.
你可以的
You can.
你现在更坚强了
You're stronger now.
而且我相信你
And I believe in you.
你选她是因为她是最好的 对吗？
You chose her 'cause she's the best, right?
那是我选她的原因之一
That's one reason I chose her.
（该让一切过去了）
该死！
Damn it!
喂？
Hello?
救救我 求你了！
Help me, please!
求你 救救我吧！
Please, help me!
我在这里面！
I'm in here!
请你救我出去
Please get me out of here.
救我啊 我…
Help me. I…
喂？
Hello?
我知道你在那
I know you're there.
求你了！ 求你救救我吧！
Please! Please help me!
我…我能听到你 求你了 回答我吧！
I… I can hear you. Please, answer me!
救我啊
Help me!
求你了！
Please!
救我！
Help me.
带我出去 求求你！
Get me out of here, please.
请救我一下吧！
Please help me.
带我出去！
Get me out of here!
求你了！
Please!
别光站着啊！
Don't just stand there!
帮帮我吧
Help me!
杰夫 当主持你的案子的法官
Jeff, when the judge presiding over your case.
给杀害你儿子的凶手定的刑 是如此的轻的时候
sentenced your boy's murderer so lightly,
你的灵魂根本没有得到治愈
your soul never recovered.
现在你拥有判他的 灵魂下地狱的权利
Now you have the power to sentence his soul straight to Hell.
或者 你也可以原谅他
Or you can forgive.
解救他的钥匙就藏在你儿子的遗物中…
The key that will free him is hidden inside your son's possessions…
这些遗物是你长久以来灵魂的寄托
Possessions you have clung to for far too long.
现在 如果你打开你脚下焚化炉的开关
Now, if you flip the switch on the incinerator underneath you,
大火将会点燃并…
a fire will cleanse you of this obsession.
吞噬所有的一切
and destroy them all,
只剩下那把钥匙
leaving only the key remaining.
同时那把钥匙也 可以让你再进一步接近
It is also the key that will bring you closer.
那个对你儿子的死负全部责任的人
to the man accountable for taking your child.
他的时间不多了 杰夫
He doesn't have much time, Jeff.
开始游戏吧
Let the game begin.
求求你 把我弄出去
Please, get me out of here.
求求你
Please!
那是什么？
What is that?
那是什么声音？
What's that sound?
我是罪犯法庭法官 看在上帝的份上！
I'm a criminal court judge, for Christ's sake!
你不能这么对我
You can't do this to me!
你不记得我了？
You don't remember me?
那好 可能你还记得蒂莫西·杨
Well, maybe you remember Timothy Young?
他是杀我儿子的那个司机
He was the driver who killed my son.
你只判了他六个月的监禁！
You gave him six months!
好吧 好吧！
Okay. All right.
我们可以谈谈这案子
We can talk about your case.
显然你是想要个答复
Obviously you want answers.
这样子也没有办法给你答复啊！
I can't give them to you like this.
真的很痛苦！
This hurts!
你给他判那么多 还是因为违章停车
You gave more for fuckin' parking tickets!
听我说
Listen to me.
我可以明白你所蒙受的巨大的痛苦
I can see that you're in a great deal of pain,
而且我们还有很多方法可以让他加刑
but there are ways that we can have his sentence extended.
我可以帮你的！
I can help you!
太迟了！
It's too late!
他们都让他走了！
They let him go!
那就不要和他一样！
Don't become what he is!
不要变成一个杀手啊！
Don't become a killer!
求你了！ 我也有个儿子
Please! I have a son, too.
你去哪？
Where are you going?
我需要你救救我！
You gotta help me!
我对不起你！
I'm so sorry!
噢.老天
Oh, God.
你正在杀害我！
You're killing me!
别这样对我！ 我快要死了！
Don't do this to me! I'm gonna die!
去你妈的！
Fuck you!
去你妈 你…
Fuck you, you…
你一定要帮帮我！
You gotta help me!
你他妈的闭嘴！
Shut the fuck up.
救命！
Help!
上来！
Come on!
他完成第二个考验了
He made it through the second test.
那法官还活着
The judge is alive.
比我预料的要快
Faster than I expected.
好了 约翰 我要 你的头保持侧身方向
All right, John, I need you to keep your head to the side.
而且要保持不动
and keep still.
这儿的问题就是你的大脑
What's goin' on here is that your brain.
你的大脑正挤压着头骨
is pushing against your skull.
我要做的就是试着帮你减压
I'm gonna try to relieve the pressure.
通过切下一片你的头骨
by cutting away a little bit of your skull.
这会治疗你的头痛
It should help you with your headaches.
并能彻底的提高你的肌能力
and drastically improve your motor skills.
你明白吗？
Do you understand?
很清楚
All too well.
好了 你可能会感到有点轻微的不适
All right, you're gonna feel some slight discomfort.
你不需要给他做全麻吗？
Are you gonna give him a general anesthetic?
这样的手术…
For a procedure like this,
病人要保持完全清醒
the patient needs to be fully alert.
好的
Okay.
阿曼达 我要你过来
Amanda, I need you here.
阿曼达
Amanda.
好了 约翰 你将 会感觉到一点压迫感
All right, John, you're gonna feel some pressure.
夹住这个 止血
Let's clamp this. Stop the bleeding.
给那注射器吸满碗里的酒精
Fill that syringe with alcohol from that bowl.
快
Hurry.
好了 约翰 我需要你把嘴闭紧点
All right, John, I need you to keep your mouth closed.
你会听到很多噪音
You're gonna hear a lot of noise.
约翰 你感觉如何？
John, how you doin'?
从没这么好过
Never better.
好了
All right.
好了 你会听到很多响声
All right, you're gonna hear a lot of ringing.
我要你一动也不动
I need you to stay very still.
我要开始了
Here I go.
好的 约翰 我现在要把头骨移开
All right, John, I'm gonna remove the skull.
他稳定了
He's stabilized.
约翰 我要你把手举起来
John, I need you to raise your hand.
并交叉手指
and flex your fingers.
约翰？
John?
约翰 把手举起来… 手…
John, raise your hand… hand…
约翰 能听见我说话吗？
John, can you hear me?
怎么了？
What's happening?
约翰
John.
他怎么了？
What's happening to him?
怎么了？
What's happening?
出了什么问题？
What's wrong?
出了什么事？
他怎么不动了？
Why isn't he moving?
做点什么啊！
Do something!
求你了
Please.
坚持住 约翰
Stay with me, John.
好
Good.
- 我爱你 - 我爱你
- I love you. - I love you.
呼吸！ 呼吸 该死！
Breathe! Breathe, damn it.
呼吸 约翰
Breathe, John.
我爱…
I love…
呼吸
Breathe.
我…
I…
我爱你
I love you.
你要把一切都交给我
You will give everything to me.
包括你身上的每一个细胞
Every cell in your body.
明白吗？
Is that understood?
是的
Yes.
你臂上的记号… 它们意味着你以前的生命
The marks on your arms… they're from another life.
我们要将那些过去丢弃
We'll leave that life behind.
一旦选择走下去…
When you go down that corridor…
就没有回头路了
there is no turning back.
你明白吗？
Do you understand that?
是的
Yes.
那从这个开始吧
Then start with this.
去吧
Go.
谁啊？
Who is that?
谁在那？
Who's in there?
我要宰了你 你这混蛋！
I'll kill you, you motherfucker!
我要杀了你 你他妈的！
把他左腿铐起来
Put his left leg in the shackle.
是时候开始我们的游戏了
It's time to start our game.
那是什么？
What's that?
减慢我的心跳
Slow my heart rate.
松弛我的肌肉
Relax my muscles.
是时候了
It's time.
出去记得把门带上
Close the door behind you.
他听不到你
He can't hear you.
他甚至就不知道你在那
He doesn't even know you're there.
阿曼达
Amanda.
把…枪…放下
Put… it… away.
相信我
Trust me.
把枪放下
Put it away.
让我们静静
Leave us alone.
现在
Now.
你这他妈的变态
You fucking freak.
我为她刚才的行为道歉
I apologize for her behavior.
她还没搞清楚情况
She swims in my sea.
到最后 她将会是一切的终点
In the end, she will be the closest.
我一直都在做各种联系
I've ever come to a connection,
让别人可以明白其中的道理
to being understood.
但是她的感情依旧是她的…软肋
But her emotion is also her… weakness.
阿达姆
Adam.
过来
Come here.
我会帮你的
I'm gonna help you.
我要让你解脱
I'm gonna free you.
阿达姆！
Adam!
（你的机会来了）
（你复仇的最后一步）
我对你儿子的事情真的很抱歉 杰夫
I'm so sorry about your son, Jeff.
不过让我告诉你一些事情 我…
But let me tell you something that I…
我确定的一件事
that I know for sure.
不管我判他什么刑 就算判500年
No sentence I gave him, not 500 years,
就算死刑 没有什么 可以摸消你内心的痛苦
not even death, nothing, will take your pain away.
而且复仇不能解决任何问题
And vengeance doesn't solve anything.
它只会让痛苦更深 杰夫
It only makes the pain greater, Jeff.
这是… 这他妈的是什么？
What the… What the fuck?
来人啊 救救我！
Somebody, help me!
这他妈的是什么啊？
What the fuck?
救命
Help.
你他妈… 你他妈的想干什么？
What the fu… What the fuck are you doin'?
求你救我
Please help me.
你好 杰夫
Hello, Jeff.
如果你听到了这个
If you are listening to this,
那意味着你长久以来 朝思暮想的 对峙
that means that the confrontation you so long dreamed of.
已经近在咫尺了
is finally unfolding.
做点什么！
Do something!
在你内心他就是那字符
In your head he is a cipher,
那些改变你生活的符号
a symbol of your life changing,
一种死亡的符号
a symbol of death.
我现在把他活生生的呈献给你
I present him to you now as a simple human being.
他的名字叫蒂莫西·杨
His name is Timothy Young.
他２７岁
He's 27 years old,
一个医学生
a medical student with a mother and a father.
和你一样有一个父亲和母亲
just like you,
他的命运在你儿子死的那天 也被彻底改变了
a man whose life also changed the day your son died.
那一天他犯了一个可怕的错误
That day he made a terrible mistake.
你认为他没有为那错误负责
You believed he didn't pay for that mistake,
而现在 你有机会让他付出代价了
and now is your chance to make him pay.
现在捆绑蒂莫西的装置 是我个人最爱
The device Timothy is strapped to is my personal favorite.
我称之为“绞架”
I call it the rack.
人类的躯体是如此奇妙
The human body is a miraculous creation.
我一直都在好奇 胳膊能扭转到什么程度吗？
Ever wonder how far the arm can twist?
这个装置就要开始扭转了
This device is going to start twisting.
然而 他还有希望活下来 如果你肯帮忙的话
There is a chance he might live, though, with your help.
求你了…
Please…
你的右边有个盒子
To your right is a box.
盒子后面就是钥匙
At the back of the box is a key.
它与猎枪的扳机相连
It's tied to the trigger of a shotgun.
你需要扪心自问的是…
The question you have to ask yourself is this…
你真的愿意…
Are you willing…
可怜可怜我吧！
Have mercy!
…为这个杀了你儿子的人挨颗子弹吗？
…to take a bullet for the man who killed your son?
俗话“以血还血 以牙还牙”
Does "Do unto others as you would have them do unto you"
在这儿真适用吗 杰夫？
apply here, Jeff?
你自己选择
Make your choice.
我的天
My God.
你一定要救他啊 杰夫！
You've got to help him, Jeff!
他妈的！
Fuck me!
请停下！停下！
Please stop! Stop!
停！请停下！
Stop! Please stop!
杰夫！
Jeff!
只是站那儿的话 你就是谋杀犯的帮凶了！
Just standing there you're an accomplice to murder!
你想做杀人犯吗？
Are you a murderer?
我每天都想杀他
I've wanted to kill him every day.
噢 上帝
Oh, my God!
整整三年了 我都想杀你
For three years, I wanted to kill you.
是啊 也许我就是
Yeah, maybe I am.
你会失去你的家庭的
You'll lose your family.
噢 老天！
Oh, my God!
你的老婆 你的女儿
Your wife, your daughter.
我要杀了他
I killed him.
操你妈的！
Fuck!
噢 老天！
Oh, God.
好吧
Okay.
挺住 孩子
Hold on, son.
挺住 别放弃
Hold on. Don't give up.
坚持住 孩子
Come on, son.
噢 老天！噢 老天！
Oh, God! Oh, God!
孩子
Son.
拿这钥匙
Got the key.
救我！
Help me!
停手！
Stop!
我原谅他！
I forgive him!
我原谅他了！不！
I forgive him! No!
不！
No!
上帝啊！
God!
你不得好死！
God damn you!
你不觉得应该
Don't you think it would be wise.
跟我聊聊天吗？
to engage me in conversation for your own sake?
谈谈你的丈夫吧
I asked you to tell me about your husband.
我们现在就好像形同陌路
It's like we're strangers now.
而且？
And?
最后一次见他时 我们都是那么的冷漠
The last time I saw him, we were so disconnected.
但现在…
But now…
我愿意献出世上的任何东西…
I'd give anything in the world…
…去见我丈夫
…to see my husband.
婚姻总是很令我向往
Matrimony's always fascinated me.
丈夫们几乎很难 看住他们的妻子
Husbands barely able to look at their wives,
妻子背着他们
wives on their backs.
在小旅店里和自以 为不错的陌生人偷情
in motel rooms with perfect strangers,
他们只顾着照料孩子 而忽视了那些事情
people who bear children only to neglect them.
的确 直到生死离别
Till death do us part, indeed.
你怎么想的我不知道
I don't know what you think you know,
但是 我们俩的婚 姻所承受过的磨难
but my marriage has survived more suffering.
你这样的人永远想象不到的
than someone like you could ever grasp.
磨难？
Suffering?
你还不知道什么是磨难呢
You haven't seen anything yet.
我这样的人？ 我是谁？
Someone like me? Who am I?
怪物
A monster.
杀人犯
A murderer.
我不会原谅杀人犯的
I don't condone murder,
而且 我还…憎恶杀人犯
and I… despise murderers.
求你
Please.
求求你…让我走吧.
Please… let me go.
我们很好 阿曼达
We're fine, Amanda.
我们不需要你
We don't need you.
我说了 我们没事儿
I said, we're fine.
如果你通过了这次考验 莲恩
If you make it through this, Lynn,
你们总有一天会像 阿曼达那样感谢我的
you're gonna thank me one day just as Amanda did.
求求你 让我走吧
Please, let me go.
我救了你的命
I saved your life.
也许你救的根本不只是我一人的命
Maybe my life isn't the one you were saving after all.
给我谈谈你的女儿吧.
Tell me about your daughter.
我知道她还是个小运动员呢
I understand she's quite a little athlete.
或者我们可以谈谈你儿子
Or we could talk about your son.
你说什么？
What did you say?
为什么你要活的如此没有生气
Why are you living with the dead.
你有一个这么美好的家庭 却不知道
when you have such a beautiful family,
丈夫总感寂寞
a husband who is indeed alone,
女儿需要母爱
a daughter who needs her mother,
病人需要一个称职的
patients who need a competent physician.
能正视他们的
who looks them in the eye.
并对他们一视同仁的医生吗？
and treats them like human beings?
他完成了第三个考验了
He's completed the third test.
恭喜 莲恩
Congratulations, Lynn.
你可以离开了
You're free to go.
对 他现在还没有出去呢
Yeah, but he's not all the way out yet.
解开那个项圈 阿曼达 让她走
Undo her collar, Amanda, and let her go.
不 他还没结束呢
No, he's not finished.
他还没完呢
He's not all the way.
阿曼达 莲恩比你想象中更重要
Amanda, Lynn is more important than you know.
解开项圈 让她走
Unlock her collar and let her go.
我说了不
I said no.
阿曼达 我们可是有规矩的
Amanda, there are rules.
我说了不行
I said no!
她不配获得自由
She doesn't deserve to go free.
你答应过的
You promised.
我答应过屁
I didn't promise you shit.
阿曼达 就算你拿着枪
Amanda, even with that gun,
莲恩 也才是掌握你生命的人
it is Lynn who holds your life in her hand.
胡扯
Fuck you.
你想让她完全控制我？
You give her control over me?
门都没有！
Fuck you!
我不会跟任何人说的 我发誓
I won't tell anyone. I promise I won't.
求求你了 我有一个家庭
Please, I have a family.
闭嘴 闭嘴！ 闭嘴 闭嘴！
Shut up, shut up, shut up, shut up!
他妈的不要乱动！
And stop fuckin' moving around!
那我们另外留下活口的 测试对象怎么办？
And what about the other test subjects that we left alive?
游戏结束
Game over.
我他妈的一定要杀了你！
I'll fucking kill you!
他们怎么办？
What about them?
你就是这样对他们的？
Was that how you felt about them?
你就是这样对 埃里克·马修斯的？
Was that how you felt about Eric Matthews?
埃里克·马修斯
Eric Matthews.
让我走
Let me go.
那我告诉你我是怎么 对埃里克·马修斯的吧
I'll tell you how I felt about Eric Matthews.
丹尼尔！
Daniel!
操！
Fuck.
丹尼尔！
Daniel!
丹尼尔？
Daniel?
操！
Fuck!
我儿子在哪？
Where's my son?
他在哪 你这该死的婊子！
Where is he, you junkie bitch?
他在哪？
Where is he?
告诉我他在哪？
Tell me where he is.
告诉我她在哪？
就他妈的在这儿！
Right fuckin' here.
你这婊子！
You bitch!
你他妈的什么都不是 婊子！
You're nothin', bitch!
你算什么东西！
You're nothing!
你不是“竖锯”
You're not Jigsaw.
你不是“竖锯” 婊子！
You're not Jigsaw, bitch!
听到了吗？
You hear me?
你算个屁！
You're nothing!
你不是“竖锯” 婊子
You're not Jigsaw, bitch.
你什么都不是
You're nothin'!
我他妈的一定要杀了你！
I'll fuckin' kill you!
不！
No!
没错
That's right.
我是个凶手
I'm a murderer.
他夺走了我的生命
He took my life from me,
所以我只是在帮他个小忙
so I just returned the fuckin' favor.
不 阿曼达 那只是你的看法
No, Amanda, that's what you thought,
但我不那么想
but I know different.
你想让他死 不是吗？
You left him for dead, didn't you?
别和我胡扯！
Stop fucking with me.
但是我清除了你的错误
But I cleaned up your mistakes.
我让你原谅他们
I forgave you for them.
让我走！求你了！
Let me go! Please!
你的所作所为和杀人犯有啥区别？
What you do is no different than murder.
你折磨他们！ 眼睁睁的看他们死！
You torture people. You watch them die.
但现在却在求我 放了这个没用婊子
But now you're begging me not to kill this worthless bitch.
就凭游戏规则这个理由？
on the grounds of some game?
你在把我们都推向 悬崖边 阿曼达
You are walking us toward a precipice, Amanda.
退后
Step back.
放屁
It's bullshit.
没人改变
Nobody changes.
全都是骗人
It's all a lie.
如果你失败了 我们就都输了
If you fail in this, we all fail.
你成功了 那就皆大欢喜
Succeed, and we all succeed.
骗人！
It's a lie!
我告诉你 她没有变
I'll tell you, she hasn't changed,
因为没有人他妈的改变
because nobody fuckin' changes.
没有人脱胎换骨
Nobody is reborn.
那全都是放屁！
It's all bullshit!
全都是他妈的胡扯！
It's all a fuckin' lie!
我只是你愚蠢游戏里的一个小卒
And I'm just a pawn in your stupid games.
我对你来说什么都不是
I don't mean anything to you.
不 你是我的一切！
No, you mean everything to me.
去你妈的！
Fuck you!
我们的命运紧连
Our fates are linked.
我一直都在尝试着帮你 阿曼达
I've tried to help you, Amanda.
那么 帮我啊！
So, help me!
改造我啊！
Fix me!
改造我啊 你这混蛋！
Fix me, motherfucker!
我就站在这儿！
I'm standin' right here.
她为什么对你这么重要？
Why is she so important to you?
她对我来说并不重要
She's not important to me.
她对你却很重要
She's important to you.
她对我不重要
She's not important to me.
我求你再考虑一下
I beg you to reconsider that.
（最后的机会）
这可是你最后的机会了 阿曼达
This is your last chance, Amanda.
她算个屁
She's nothing.
你的时间不多了
Your time's running out.
现在 你再想想你在做什么
Now, you think about what you're doing.
想想你做过的一切
Think about everything that you've done.
想想你答应过我的话
You think about what you promised me.
想想我们的梦想
Think about our dreams.
想想明天
Think about tomorrow.
莲恩？
Lynn?
杰夫！杰夫…
Jeff! Jeff…
莲恩
Lynn.
- 莲恩 - 杰夫
- Lynn. - Jeff.
你刚刚毁掉了你的生命！
You just destroyed four lives.
你刚杀了杰夫的妻子
You just murdered Jeff's wife.
宝贝儿
Baby.
阿曼达
Amanda.
没事的
It's okay.
这是你的考验…
This was your test…
…你的游戏
…your game.
我想怎么样？
What do I want?
我想玩个游戏
I want to play a game.
你将被考验
You're being tested.
你的意志将被考验…
Your will is being tested…
你将要使一个人活着
Your will to keep someone alive.
你能做到吗？
Can you do that?
你能遵守规则 将生命作为礼物赐予某人吗？
Can you follow the rules and grant someone the gift of life?
我是在考验你啊
I was testing you.
我把你带来
I took you in.
你就要把一切都交给我
You will give everything to me.
明白
Yes.
包括身体的每一个细胞
Every cell in your body.
我选择了你并以让你 继承我一生的工作为荣
I selected you for the honor of carrying on my life's work.
但你却没有
But you didn't.
没错
That's right.
我是个杀人犯
I'm a murderer.
我憎恶杀人犯
I despise murderers.
你根本没有在考验人们求生的意志
You didn't test anyone's will to live.
游戏结束
Game over.
相反你夺走了他们唯一的机会
Instead you took away their only chance.
你的游戏根本没有赢家
Your games were unwinnable.
你的考验对象只是你的牺牲品
Your subjects merely victims.
你
You.
那没有回头路了
There is no turning back.
明白吗？
Do you understand that?
绝望之下 我决定给你最后一次机会
In my desperation, I decided to give you one last chance.
所以我将一切就位
So I put everything in place.
你选她是因为她是最好的 对吗？
You chose her 'cause she's the best, right?
那是我选她的原因之一
That's one reason I chose her.
但你不知道莲恩和杰夫是夫妻
You didn't know that Lynn and Jeff were husband and wife.
为了达到游戏的目的 我没有告诉你这一点
I had to keep that from you for the purposes of my game.
我不得不省略 他们破碎的婚姻生活
I had to leave out the ruined marriage,
偷情的妻子
the cheating wife,
满心复仇的丈夫 孤独的女儿
the vengeful husband, the neglected daughter.
并且我让你自己做了选择
And I let you make your own choices.
我希望你能成功
I wanted you to succeed.
阿曼达 把枪放下
Amanda, put it away.
相信我 就算你拿着枪
Trust me, even with that gun,
莲恩才是掌握你生命的人
it's Lynn who holds your life in her hands.
她对我不重要
She's not important to me.
我求你再考虑一下
I beg you to reconsider that.
解开项圈 让她走
Unlock her collar and let her go.
我说了不！
I said no!
我们游戏的规则很清楚
The rules of our game have been made very clear.
而且你必须得遵守规则
You need to abide by those rules.
你没能做到
You couldn't.
上帝
God.
游戏结束
Game over.
你今晚什么都没学到 对吗？
You haven't learned anything tonight, have you?
你的愤怒和仇恨 只能伤害到你所爱的人
Your rage and your vengeance will only hurt the ones you love.
杀了我只能让你更加痛苦
Killing me will only add to your misery.
那样是换不回你的儿子的
It will not bring back your son.
想想你的女儿吧 杰夫
Think of your daughter, Jeff.
她现在比任何时候都更需要你
She needs you now more than ever.
你不能杀我的 杰夫
You can't kill me, Jeff.
你妻子快死了 杰夫
Your wife's dying, Jeff.
她的时间不多了
Her time's running out.
杰夫 不要弄错了
Jeff, do not miscalculate.
你的命运在我手中
Your fate is in my hands.
你妻子的命运在我手中
Your wife's fate is in my hands.
我爱你
I love you.
我带你回家 好吗？
I'm taking you home. Okay?
即使 你可能没看到威胁…
Though you may not see any threat…
但威胁无处不在
there are threats all around you.
杰夫 你如果要试着移动你的妻子 她就会死
Jeff, if you try to move your wife, she will die.
我可以在四分钟内叫来一辆救护车
I can have an ambulance here in four minutes.
你希望今晚把妻子带走吗？
Would you like to take your wife out of here tonight?
你希望带她去个安全的地方吗？
Would you like to take her to safety?
留下
Stay.
待在这儿面对我 杰夫
Stand and face me, Jeff.
- 留下来陪我 求你 - 现在
- Stay with me, please. - Right now.
想找回你以前的生活吗？
Would you like to get your life back?
想吗 杰夫？
Would you, Jeff?
我可以令你实现梦想
I can make that happen.
选哪个呢 杰夫？
Which is it, Jeff?
来吧…是或不是？
Come on… yes or no?
好
Yes.
你想怎样？
What do you want?
最后一个考验
One final test.
规则很简单
The rules are simple.
那张桌子上有很多邪恶的工具…
Over on that table, there's a host of vicious implements…
每一个都可以激发你庞 大的肉躯下内心的欲望
which you can use to exact your pound of flesh,
让你用来复仇
to take your vengeance,
让你放纵自己杀戮的妄想
to indulge your obsession.
或是你放弃仇恨
Or you can choose to put your vengeance aside,
选择宽恕与原谅
and you can forgive.
你可以原谅我带给你的诅咒
You can forgive me for the pain.
以及我给你和你的妻子带来的痛苦
that I've caused you and your wife tonight.
杰夫
Jeff.
何去何从 杰夫？
Which is it gonna be, Jeff?
亲爱的 不要！
Honey, don't do it.
杰夫…
Jeff…
你决定
It's up to you.
我需要你
I need you.
是生是死 杰夫？
Live or die, Jeff?
你自己决定
Make our choice.
我原谅你
I forgive you.
杰夫…
Jeff…
杰夫 杰夫！
Jeff. Jeff!
杰夫 不要！
Jeff, no.
我原谅你
I forgive you.
你好 杰夫
Hello, Jeff.
我录制了这盘带子 以防万一
I made this tape as an insurance policy, if you will.
杰夫！
Jeff!
如果你现在在听这个的话 那就表示是时候收尾了
And if you're listening to it, then it's time to collect.
我是你宽恕之心的最终考验
I was your final test of forgiveness.
但如果你听到这个
And if you are listening to this,
那说明你失败了
then you failed.
现在你必须要付出代价…
Now you must pay the price…
只为复仇而活所付的代价
the price for living for nothing but vengeance.
现在我要给你一些活下去的启示
Now I will give you something to live for.
我告诉了你 你不能杀我的 杰夫
I told you that you couldn't kill me, Jeff,
但我没说过为什么
but I didn't tell you why,
答案很简单
and the answer is simple.
我是那个应对你损失的孩子负责的人
I am the person responsible for the loss of your child.
我是唯一知道你女儿下落的人
I am the only person who knows where your daughter is.
她待的地方的空气 可没那么多 杰夫
She only has a limited supply of air, Jeff,
而且 如果你想找回她
and if you want to get her back,
你就必须玩个游戏
you'll have to play a game.
杰夫！
Jeff!